[Music]
w
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome back to the asket show we
are in episode
210 I hope everybody is doing great
fantastic brilliant outstanding so let's
see who all is there in the live stream
I can see random skull pritam Sharma
Mohit Pand kov ji um maheswari Niha
tomor GSR young Sonic Anita sashan
dearam anol sanoli skp Yogi nothing P
Sharma kanade loone Rider Dr suak dagar
lero online hello notan Vikram
geopolitical Mech ech Vidant bavik
vadera Krish sha cou practics gamer
asbest
chavada mitun SP hi shagun Chopra
namaskar pray Paul good evening Surendra
Gupta K Singh Neen Sam Satish niharika
Gupta surj s gorov
GSR desap yumnam yumnam young Sonic
again geopolitical dub Dr Atul pritam
Sharma pram banery pan Kumar Singh
sashan deas
deas Sam sahu lone Rider Sigma Amit
vasel Sumit Rana nothing Shri sham Kumar
joal Singh Mohit parashar geopolitical
du sksm push Moria Summit statement
gorov van Kumar Sharma ad tagi kushbu
Kumar skin letter niharika gup parik
Mukesh surbi sh Deepak ryang wangi Bara
edit Vikram ADI Matrix May utur BB dick
gamer
Raj and so many other people okay let me
stop greeting you all at that point I'm
going to take questions that you have
asked in the comments lots of questions
in the comments as always I'm going to
take the best of those as many as I can
I'm going to answer a bunch of those and
then if there is time remaining left
over then I will take questions from the
live chat
so with that said let us get into the
questions where are the questions what
questions do we have today let us
see okay there's it's a couple of
questions Akash and Vidant P Canada is
trying to to send students after studies
send students back after studies and
it's trying to stop the immigration as
many students find jobs and try to
acquire citizenship there what's your
take on this Canada plans to deport
inter students the European people also
wants immigrant also want immigrants
gone if such Mass deportation happens
where do you think these people will go
how will the Indians that come back to
India after being deported how will it
affect India will deported Bangladesh is
try to enter India or will they prefer
living in the country with his new
government which they claim is
democratic and better than the so-called
fascist and communal Indian government
okay yes Canada Canada is a strange
Nation the the fudo regime is a strange
regime on the one hand you have Donald
Trump Trump who wants to be reelected as
president of the US and he has said that
America needs skilled immigrants high
quality immigrants not low quality
immigrants so he says that anyone who
gets any student from another country
who gets a degree in the US whether it's
a diploma or a master's degree
bachelor's degree whatever PhD once you
get the degree you will also be given a
green card a permanent residency
residency in the US the right to live
there permanently that's what Trump has
said he's kind of promised that in one
one of the podcasts that he did so Trump
wants high quality immigrants to stay in
the US he wants this nation to attract
the best quality immigrants and he
doesn't want the low quality unskilled
people that's that are pouring into the
country that's Trump's attitude on the
other hand you have the Trudeau regime
and Trudeau wants the lowquality
immigrants he wants those unskilled
people who come from certain specific
parts of the world generally young ma
males military age
males belonging to certain parts of the
world with a certain kind of culture and
religions that's what he wants and he
doesn't want the high quality
hardworking talented immigrants that
generally come from Nations like India
China Etc he doesn't want
those I don't I fail to understand what
motivates and drives this individual
Justin
tudo so you know Trump has been
criticized in the past especially when
he was president for calling certain
countries what he called hole
countries right that's that's the term
he used okay not my term his term so I
think Justin Kudo wants to turn Canada
into a hole country that's what
he's trying to do what else can I
say he wants the lowest quality
immigrants he the moment they touch down
the moment they land at the airport he
will stand at the airport and and and
issue the passport on the on the spot
he's done that in the past okay that's
the low quality unskilled God knows what
quality immigrants but the ones who come
through the proper Channel Through the
due process due proper process and who
study hard and work really hard and
prove themselves he wants to deport them
what a
loser that's just inudo for you what's
my take on this I mean I don't get it
but okay good for us see the problem
with IND in India is that we have this
terrible education system and terrible
overall quality of life right things are
improving slowly uh but there's a lot of
problems still there's corruption there
is red tape there's there's a lack of
opportunities there's this horrible
education system and so on so people in
India especially youngsters they want to
go abroad and have a better life and
Canada was one of the destinations that
kind of attracted Indians nowadays not
quite so much
right so because of this because of
these conditions within India we have
been experiencing what we call the brain
drain for decades everyone talks about
it but nobody in the government does a
thing about
it so uh if Canada starts deporting
people back to their home countries lots
of Indians will have to come back well
uh bad for those individuals but overall
I would say good for for the good for
the country I'm sure they will try and
go elsewhere they'll try their best
they've already already tried to go
abroad they I'm sure they'll be able to
if possible go somewhere else if if they
are lucky otherwise good for India they
all to find jobs in India and work in
India uh overall it's bad for those
people I feel obviously feel sorry for
them India I would say that we should
instead of glutting about this and
saying good for us we should we should
try and improve our system right I'm I
know that the the current government is
is doing is taking steps to ameliorate
the system things make things better do
it faster do it better I would say uh so
these Indians who come back to India in
case they deported they will not affect
India in any bad bad way not at all
absolutely not at all uh deported
Bangladesh is well well well okay listen
deported Bangladesh is go back to
Bangladesh you have a country of your
own you be there it's clearly a better
country as you say you you you have
democracy Now like you didn't have
before will enjoy the
democracy
e e
audible now I am hoping that I'm
audible no buo audio still audio back
back
now is it back is the audio
back um hello yes I think the audio is
back yes okay okay sometimes these
things happen I wonder sometimes why it
happens uh three-letter agenes somebody
is
saying okay no issues no issues we we
are back we back no issues I just
reconnected the thing to another Port
that's all okay so what was I saying I
was talking about Pakistan right this
question has the process of
disintegration of Pakistan already
started and what about the situation in
baluchistan the bla baluchistan
Liberation Army apparently killed over
100 Pakistani Punjabi soldiers will this
spill go bad with the US and they will
try and destroy the bla because of Iran
what's the deal okay so first of all
let's deal let's address Anita's
question has the process of
disintegration of Pakistan already
started the process has been in process
for quite some time there are so many
forces within
Pakistan that seek to destroy the
country that that want the country To Go
in different directions
there are so many ethnic groups that are
disenfranchised that that are
marginalized in the country there are so
many people who are oppressed in
Pakistan so it's natural to have these
forces within Pakistan that want out of
the country that no longer want to be
under the heavy boot of the Pakistani
military machine so that process has
been going on so why is Pakistan still a
unified country it's because it is
useful to external powers for the
longest time the Pakistan nation was
created by by the British to serve the
British geopolitical interests in the
subcontinent and and the broader region
then in around 1956
1958 the UK seized to be a First Rate
geopolitical power they became a second
rate geopolitical power and then the
Americans took over so the pakistanis
became a Us wasal in the 50s late 50s
and the the Americans uh sought to use
Pakistan as a counterbalance to India
then the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan
happened in Pakistan became extremely
important to the US
geopolitically
then uh obviously as an anti-india Force
also the Americans used Pakistan they
funded and financed Pakistani ter
terrorism in India for decades the
Americans then for a brief time a decade
or so Pakistan was China's vasal they
called each other the iron Brothers then
after the 2022 coup in which Imran Khan
was ousted Pakistan once again is in the
US Camp so as long as Pakistan is useful
to a much more powerful Nation Pakistan
will remain
United Okay Pakistan will remain United
as long as the US needs
Pakistan so it's always on the brink of
collapse it's on the brink of being a
failed State it's on the brink of
disintegration but it doesn't quite
disintegrate because the Americans keep
on propping it
up and that's going to continue as long
as the Americans find any utility in
Pakistan and India is is a growing
Nation India is the fourth most powerful
nation in the world India will soon
become the third largest economy India
is on track to become a great power so
Pakistan is very important for the us as
long as they and and the Americans want
to curtail India's growth they want to
restrict constrain restrict whatever you
want to say India's growth they don't
want India to grow and achieve its
potential because they see India as a
long-term threat I understand their
perspective nothing wrong with that they
they the only superpower and they want
to stay the only superpower forever
essentially and any
potential competitor or adversary far on
the horizon has to be dealt with so
that's how they see it there's nothing
nothing personal it's all business like
the Americans say you know like like
they
say so as long as that is the case
Pakistan will remain important for them
and they will ensure that Pakistan keeps
on existing so that's where we are
temporary Nation artificial Nation but
it's going to continue to exist for some
time
for let's say the sh short term
foreseeable to short to medium-term
foreseeable future now what is the
situation baluchistan well we had this
uh in incident a few days ago right uh
there was this coordinated series of
attacks uh by of operations by The
bistan Liberation Army that the Freedom
Fighters of bistan against the Pakistani
armed forces and they killed over 100 uh
Pakistani oppressors soldiers whatever
you want to call them I happen to be
in an in Indian military base when this
news broke out so that was interesting
yeah um so that's where I first heard
this news I was in an Indian military
base when this when I first heard this
news anyhow that's a that's a that's
beside the point so uh yes the bla The
bistan Liberation Army is doing
well they may have some linkages with
the
Taliban the Taliban is an interesting
organization with linkages of their own
outside the country but that's a
different matter so I think uh the bla
is is it's doing rather well for for for
the cause of the liberation of
baluchistan from Pakistan I wish them
well the Pakistani army is an oppressive
Force they need to be obviously well um
but bistan needs to be liberated so does
sy so does pojk Pakistani occup Jammu
Kashmir so does Gil ban
Pakistan occupied part of G ban and so
much more the it needs to return to um
gandhar Afghanistan So eventually this
will happen uh will the Americans try
and destroy the bla baluchistan
Liberation Army look as long as their
overall geopolitical interests are not
hit too bad the Americans won't care too
much about The baluchistan Liberation
Army it's only if us assets are hit as
long as a few Pakistani soldiers die
here and there the Americans don't care
look for the the us Pakistan is nothing
different from
Ukraine in a in a certain
way the Americans don't care how many
Ukrainian soldiers die Ukraine is is is
Canon fter for the for the
Americans they want the Ukrainian
soldiers to die in in for the cause of
of of uh uh
weakening the the
Russians so as long as the Russians keep
on the the war continues and the
Russians from their perspective are
weakened they don't care how many ukra
ukrainians Die similarly the Pakistani
army and their soldiers they're
Expendable assets for the Americans 100
soldiers what's the big deal for the
Americans they don't care did not the BL
has not hit any American targets any
American assets they've hit Pakistani
soldiers killed more than 100 no big
deal I'm sure the Americans will issue
some kind of verbal uh condemnation of
whatever I'm not sure if they issue that
or if they will but they may at some
point but as long as the bla does not
hit American targets and and American
assets and Target American assets the
Americans don't care this is a Pakistani
problem to solve and as long as the
Americans are are untouched they don't
care so yeah that's the
deal okay Bangladesh let's talk about
Bangladesh shall we so I have been
saying right I've been saying for quite
some time that if this this coup in
which shik H was outed if it was really
a
students student Revolution which
succeeded then why are there no student
leaders in the B the the Bangladesh
government so now here's what we hear
okay uhon CH and Cobra WAP so iion Chri
says you are wrong here there are
currently two student leaders serving as
advisers of Ministry of information and
Ministry of Youth and sports nah
whatever and Asif whatever okay and you
much like the other Indian analysts keep
failing to understand the Bangladesh
scenario there are two students in the
current government of Bangladesh and
also another student leader appointed as
the Special Assistant to the chief
advisor which itself is a post
equivalent to cabinet minister so the
students are represented in this new
government oh yes baby all right right I
congratulate the students of Bangladesh
you have been represented in this
government so after hearing my repeated
criticism it looks like the Bangladeshi
regime has appointed a few students to
some nominal
positions minister of advisor to the
ministry of Youth and sports a Ministry
that has no real function and and what
Ministry of adviser to the ministry of
information so you are appointed a
student is appointed as an advisor to a
Ministry an irrelevant Ministry and
another student is appointed as an
advisor to another irrelevant Ministry
and a third student is a special
assistant to the chief
adviser of something or the other do you
even see what they are
doing they are taking you for complete
fools and you people are falling for
that I mean you deserve to be called
whatever you're being
called do you even understand what is
being done to
you after hearing all this criticism
they have appointed some students like
two three students to some Rand to some
irrelevant position which is equivalent
to something but is not that
something why is a student leader not
the prime minister of Bangladesh why is
a student leader not the defense
Minister foreign minister Finance
Minister of Bangladesh why are the
student leaders advisers to some random
irrelevant Ministries are you people
even able to see what this regime is
doing to you or are you that
stupid come on my Bangladeshi friends
you are not stupid you have the same
amount of brains as Indians we are the
same people
genetically use that that gay M matter
the gods have given you use it you you
are being fooled and you are falling for
it you're falling for
it no no wonder there are some
reasonably intelligent people in
Bangladesh who are who have restarted
the student protests against the current
regime because they have completely
fooled you they have used the student
protests as the as the nice convenient
excuse to take over power to get rid of
shikina and and essentially install what
is essentially a military government in
Bangladesh that is what it is
this current regime is actually a
military regime in Bangladesh because
know was outed by the Bangladeshi
military and now they have put a nice
puppet in front of the
military that unus you whatever that guy
is the the the the noble laurate older
than older than Biden that guy right
he's just a pu and he just a figure head
they will come and say haha nice nice
things the real power is your military
you're back to military rule that's
what's happened to you your economy is
going to go down the the drain now watch
watch
me wait and watch what happens your
economy is going to go down the drain
Law and Order is going to isn't
great that's where Bangladesh is headed
and like in case you don't wake up you
deserve
it okay mavin and master Prince
Bangladesh has ordered some military
tanks and other weapons from Pakistan
are they planning to attack the
chicken's
sck why is Bangladesh buying weapons
from Pakistan why doesn't India have any
hegemony over these small neighboring
countries okay so what is going on let's
first of all what's the chicken neck I'm
sure you we are all aware but let's take
a very brief look at the chicken's neck
it is the Siliguri Corridor this roughly
25 24 kilometer wide patch of
land that connects uh what we call
so-called Mainland India with the
so-called Northeast or far east of India
that is the chicken's neck and so why is
Bangladesh ordering all these weapons
from Pakistan by the way Bangladesh also
has a chicken's
neck you know this part of the territory
it's also about 32 33 kilometers wide
and that connects the cigo the the
chattogram region to the rest of
Bangladesh it's about 1if of the
territory of Bangladesh can be is is at
the mercy of the Bangladeshi chicken's
neck by the way in case we haven't seen
the map or paid too much attention to it
but coming back to the question why is
Bangladesh ordering arms and ammunition
weapons and whatever else from Pakistan
are they planning to attack the
chicken's snake
look no matter how many weapons or
whatever the Bangladesh is get from
Pakistan look I I assure you they're not
trying they're not planning to attack
the chicken snake Okay militarily if
they try it then Bangladesh will cease
to
exist they simply I mean there's no
question of what happens if Bangladesh
launches an actual military assault on
the chicken's neck it's over Bangladesh
you
finished uh India is just way too
powerful just a simple fact no matter
how much bravado the Bangladesh is put
out look we are not eny
Nations we we should not be talking
about these things so so then why are
they if they don't plan to attack the
chicken's neck what are they planning to
do see
Pakistan is
a long time greatly well experienced
vasal state of the US they have Decades
of experience dealing with the Americans
and being their
wasal okay they know how to deal with
the
Americans Bangladesh is a newly Meed
vasal state so they need some training
right so Pakistan will give them the
training so when you have a great highly
experienced wasal and a newly
experienced a new
you want them to talk to each other and
work together so that the new wasal is
quickly brought up to date as to how to
so it's about training you know and you
want them to have coordination and
Synergy because they're both anti-india
vasal they the objective of having these
two Wass is to constrain India is is
it's to it's to contain India isn't
it
so that's what's happening the Americans
are having their wasal talk to each
other and and deal together work
together uh
it's essentially we are back to the old
days of East Pakistan West Pakistan
that's where we are so that's why
Bangladesh is buying this weapon from
Pakistan it's to send a message to India
it's to create the right kind of synergy
and coordination and cooperation between
the two vels and so on that's what it is
Bangladesh is in no position to attack
the chicken neck they would be
obliterated if they tried that it would
be complete game over for Bangladesh if
they do that but what they could do is
they could uh you know the Border as we
know is us it's a very open border
because of a variety of reasons which I
will not go into and they could try and
infiltrate all kinds of miscreant and
various kinds of characters and various
kinds of terrorist elements Etc into the
Indian over the border into the Indian
Territory to create all kinds of
problems and Siliguri is a very
sensitive area and they could try doing
that they are not stupid or fool Hardy
enough to launch an actual military
assault it's not like vajpai is prime
minister right in case you don't
remember during the vajpai times there
was an attack by Bangladesh on I think
the was it the
crpf BSF I think BSF and a whole large
number of BSF soldiers were killed by
the bangladeshis BSF
soldiers and the vajpai regime did
nothing so this is not that India so uh
I don't think the Bangladesh's will try
and do that anything like that but they
will you will see an uptick of of
infiltration attempted infiltration and
all kinds of problems in the entire
region whether it is into West Bengal
the Siliguri region the Far East of
India tripura wherever you will see that
you're going to see that increasing we
GNA we are essentially going back very
soon to the days of East Pakistan days
when we had East Pakistan instead of
Bangladesh so that is the deal that's
where we are
going mcloven says so iscon was
Distributing food in Bangladesh floods
after the Bangladesh's destroyed iscon
temples do you think it's a stupid thing
to do
it may not be a stupid thing to do uh
let me tell you why you know every
cause every great cause needs
matters this is something we we have to
learn from the abrahamic
religions you know when Christianity was
in its nent stage you know newborn
religion
Etc uh today we are taught that there
was a tremendous amount of Oppression of
the early Christians by the
Romans right and apparently the Romans
would persecute them and and kill them
and all and those early people who were
killed Christians who were allegedly
killed by the Romans were the early
great
Martyrs
and this movement Christianity used this
this persecution as the fuel to justify
it its rise okay and then when the shoe
came on the other foot
and when Christianity was on the ascent
my goodness the kind of Terror they
Unleashed on the old civilizations of
Europe my goodness it was a sight to
behold they destroyed
everything so when they for example
there was some some Christian preacher
who went to
um which old name
Armenia okay Armenia was a was a Hindu
Zoran Nation Armenia look up the map I
not show the map I don't I don't think I
should show the map every time look it
up where is Armenia Armenia 2,000 plus
years ago was a Hindu zorran Nation
Nation you still have a Hindu fire
temple in the region in aeran today but
that that used to be Armenia Baku used
to be Armenia now it is aeran aeran is a
new nation okay compared to Armenia
which is old so in Armenia some
Christian preacher comes there and he
starts preaching and converting
people and he Alle ly apparently is
punished to die by faying faying means
you remove the skin of an individual of
a person a horrible way of killing
people but the Christians used to do it
regularly in the Middle Ages Middle Ages
you know the the the punishment one of
the punishments for heresy and blasphemy
Etc was either crucifixion or burning at
the stake or faying alive and there are
paintings of people being fling alive
being fled Alive by
Christians the Christian by Christian by
the church and all that so um this
Christian preacher goes to Armenia I
don't know which how many years ago
roughly 2,000 years ago give or take and
he's trying to preach Christianity and
convert people to Christianity and he's
sentenced to death by being F flayed
allegedly and there is this painting of
him standing without his skin and
holding his entire skin in his hand and
he still has a stern look on his face
and he's a great martyr and these are
the stories that that that brought forth
indignation among people whether the the
stories are true or not doesn't matter
but these martys were the driving force
of Christianity it gave Christianity
this imped us that you know we have this
righteous cause and people are are are
oppressing us they are martyring us and
we will take this forward for the for
the sake of the martyrs they have made
so many sacrifices for our cause and now
we will take it Forward on their behalf
that's the kind of missionary Zeal they
would have so that's something we can
kind of learn from the from the rahic
religions so uh I'm not saying it's good
that people get killed and iscon temples
are destroyed but it's going to
happen when isan operates when a Hindu
organization operates in a hostile land
like Bangladesh they're going to have
they're going to face this persecution
they going to face this
oppression and you carry forth you carry
on despite the
oppression so that's just how it is you
can either withdraw and and and V ha the
land and give it up or you stay in
fight so I think I don't think it's
really a stupid thing to
do it it gives them the moral High
Ground for sure doesn't it so it's about
being persistant staying there yes you
will have setbacks your temples will be
destroyed your people will be attacked
some people unfortunately will be killed
this a Hindu genocide going on in
Bangladesh but you don't step back I
think that's what I've said advocated in
the past that Bangladeshi Hindus should
not seek to flee to India it's their
land stand and fight and India should
support them should give them material
and moral support especially material
support uh the borders are poers for a
change let's make it work to our
advantage uh shre bansel says us
diplomats recently met some politicians
in Jammu and Kashmir how are they
allowed to do that who are they to meet
local politicians in foreign
countries look
diplomats what is the purpose of having
diplomats what what is the diplomats
do
diplomats are your representatives to a
foreign
country and their job is
to from one perspective to build Bridges
between the two count countries to
ensure that there is proper flow of
communication and messaging between the
two countries to put forth your
perspective your government's
perspective to the host government and
its its various representatives and
organs and also the purpose of
diplomats is to um create a conducive
atmosphere and environment in their host
country for their own country seek out
opportunities talk to people seek out
Partners seek out wellwishers seek
out citizens and various uh you know
industrialists uh business people Etc
who are pro-india cultivate them all of
this is part of
diplomacy so you as a diplomat you
certainly can meet politicians it's part
of your daily
job you go look I am I'm not a diplomat
I've never been a diplomat I'm just
saying how I see diplomacy you create a
database essentially of if you are an
Indian Diplomat you create database of
pro-indian forces and elements in
whichever country you are based in
because that can come in
handy your job is to advance your
nation's interests in every possible
legal way hopefully okay of course there
are military atach in various embassies
the Americans have a significant number
of military aach and defense AES in
various countries every single
country when you have a military
attaches Etc many of them are spies
essentially you know they're given
technical designations some are chefs
some are Cooks some are gardeners some
are what not but many of them are
actually spies so that's essentially
what diplomacy is it is something and it
is also something which is not supposed
to be and every nation plays this game
the Israelis have a very clear rule okay
if a member of the Israeli Defense
Forces IDF if a serving member of the
IDF accepts a car
ride from a car that has diplomatic
license plates that person is Court
Marshal because Israel regards every
single foreign Diplomat on their
territory to be a
spy and I think that is the correct way
of looking at
it so um so diplomats there's something
wrong with
diplomats meeting with various
political uh politicians members of
various political parties in the host
country including opposition parties
that is
allowed it is
allowed but of course it can be seen as
interference in Internal Affairs and
most likely to some extent it is so what
can you do about that is the question
let's take the case of
China in
China there is no there is no opposition
right there's only one political party
the Chinese Communist party now there
are some people in China who are kind of
uh you could say dissidents is the word
they use who kind of want more freedom
more democracy Etc and I'm sure the
American diplomats Etc over there would
want to meet those people are they
allowed to meet them no
the Chinese government ensures that the
American diplomats can't meet such
people so why can't India do that well
India is not China China is a whole
different category of nation China is
much more powerful than India China has
much more leverage on the US than India
the US economy the US market is
dependent on China on Chinese exports
the Chinese have a tremendous amount of
Leverage Chinese economy is much larger
than India's economy what leverage does
India have on the US that could be that
that would allow us to refuse certain
things we right now don't have that much
leverage we have a lot of dependency on
the US do you understand how it works at
the end of the day what you can and
cannot do depends on the amount of hard
power and leverage that you
have so right now the Americans can get
away with all this they're clearly
interfering and meddling in the internal
affairs of India and they can get get
away with it and I promise you I promise
you look at what the Americans are doing
in Europe they are doing much
worse look at what they're doing in
Japan they are doing far worse the
Japanese the Europeans the Koreans Etc
have to keep quiet and swallow their
pride and just bear with
it we are not there we are in a much
better position understand this but yes
this is part of the the deal when you
when you are dealing with a way more
powerful Nation a superpower there are
things that you simply have to quietly
swallow and what if India said no you
are not allowed to meet so and so person
India could have done that well then the
Americans would have punished India in a
variety of ways and citizens won't even
be able to understand why they have
taken such certain actions but the
government of India will understand so
we don't want to antagonize the US let
them interfere a little bit to some
extent our job is to quietly get bigger
and stronger that's what
understand
that so until we be we become a genuine
tiger we can't behave like a tiger right
now we are a cat a reasonably large
house cat but we are still a cat we are
not the tiger we have to become a tiger
it will take us 20 30 years and the
Americans don't want us to become a
tiger they want us to remain a nice
little house cat so that is the push and
pull that we are experiencing there we
are anti-human 518 says is Dr J
Shankar's diplomacy failing some
commentators say Modi sidelined him and
visited Ukraine also Mr rajat Singh
signed a contract in collaboration of
arms and ammunition with the US I don't
get what's currently going on is Indian
diplomacy going well or
bad so
listen I've been I've been advised not
to use
certain adjectives when describing
political commentators so how shall
I how shall I describe these political
commentators this geopolitical
commentators I would say that they're
trying to chase wisdom but wisdom has
always run faster than them these
commentators who say
this so apparently some commentator has
said that Modi sidelined Jo Shankar and
visited
Ukraine right so whichever commentator
said that I sure that that person that
those people are chasing wisdom but
wisdom has been always running faster
than them now the here's the deal Mod's
visit to Ukraine was not some great
piece of cake that Modi has always
wanted to do this was a curtsy visit
there is no National interest in US
visiting
Ukraine Modi would have been the
happiest person to delegate this to J
Shankar and J Shankar I'm I sure you was
very happy that he did not have to go to
Ukraine his boss had to go to Ukraine
because there was no point going to
Ukraine it is simply a curtsy visit done
to Plate the
Americans so there's no question of Modi
sidelining J Shankar and visiting
Ukraine he would have actually wanted
Jan to go in his behalf but the
Americans must have insisted just to
plade them Modi
went okay now is J Shankar's diplomacy
failing look diplomacy is what happens
behind closed doors diplomacy is not the
wonderful sound bites that you give and
wonderful speeches that you make and
those laser eyes that are shown of J
Shankar that's not diplomacy diplomacy
is what happens behind closed doors
something that you never ever see and
you don't even know what what it is like
that's what diplomacy
is Jan's diplomacy is not failing he's
carrying out his duties as as usual okay
these geopolitical Geniuses who make
these statements I can assure you that
wisdom keeps on eluding them despite
them chasing it rajat Singh signed a
contract on collaboration with arms and
amunition well you got to do things
right you got to do things you've got to
plade the superpower you live in you
live in a part in in in in a jungle with
this gigantic Tyrannosaurus Rex and you
simply a cat you've got to keep
tyranosaurus Rex
happy you are not a tiger you are a cat
right now understand where India stands
on the geopolitical stage it is the
world's fourth most powerful Nation
India India's hard power score is 4.9
the US
94 do you understand the gigantic
difference between
4.9 and
94 okay China is about 16 or whatever
and Russia is 54 56 India is nowhere in
to be compared with the us or Russia
or even China China is about three and a
half times more powerful than India so
when you are small you act your size
okay don't try to be all big and make
statements then it comes back to bite
you so India is doing the right thing
you've got to Plate the Americans you
got to play the game keep everybody
happy and quietly buy your buy your time
hide your strength buy your time keep
growing slowly slowly slowly and do
whatever is in your National interest
that's what's happening Jo Shankar's
diplomacy is not
failing Modi isn't sidelining anyone
rajna Singh is doing whatever it takes
to take India forward of course we could
have we could do things in a different
way in a variety of ways but look leave
it to the government I mean we are who
are we to judge the government are we
running the government when you run the
government you come to know so many
things that you can't
handle you simply can't handle those
things we essentially who are outside
the government we have no access to
classified information top secret
information we we don't have the correct
picture of the world it's very easy to
sit here and criticize let's not do that
let's support government as long as
they're in
power uh Sun Moon 08 says do you think
Mr modi's visit to Ukraine reduces his
brand and is that what the US wanted
look Mr Modi visiting Ukraine it it
doesn't mean that his brand is
declining it doesn't it doesn't indicate
a decline of his
brand but but one could
say to a certain extent that him not
getting 273 seats and a full majority in
Parliament is a decline of his
brand that is a decline of the brand
Modi visiting Ukraine is not a decline
of brand Modi that is something he would
have had to do anyway so that's how I
see it a brand every brand look what is
a brand a brand is a name right apple is
a brand Microsoft is a brand Tesla is a
brand El musk is a brand Donald Trump is
a brand Narendra Modi is a brand
Vladimir Putin sh Jinping and so on so
forth you can go on forever the point is
every
brand India is a brand by the way okay
and so on so Brands rise and fall rise
and fall um in case of human beings you
have a certain limited lifespan 80 90
100 years whatever um and uh brand means
your reputation your relevance
Etc look look Mr Modi I would say is
going to be in power for one more term
by 2029 I don't see him being the next
prime minister candidate so by 29 his
brand will be less relevant clearly and
somebody else hopefully will be the next
prime Minal candidate that's how I see
it because India needs a now the next
prime ministerial candidate from the BJP
needs to be a much younger and much more
Dynamic person Mr Modi has done a
tremendous amount of work that last 10
years in he still has five more years to
go and I I wish him the very best I hope
he does even better than the past 10
years but at some point in time you got
to step up step down right 15 years in
power I think it's enough So eventually
he's going to have to uh uh step down
and and and hand over the baon to a
younger
person so by that time I would say by 29
his brand will be definitely less
relevant than somebody else brand may be
rising by the time some newer leader
perhaps so I think you could you could
perhaps look at it that way perhaps okay
that 2024 the election represents the
beginning of the decline of the brand
perhaps but I don't see this Ukraine
visit as being relevant to as being a
sign as as being a
signifier that the brand is declining or
or it's something that contributes to uh
the decline of his brand I don't see
that way
Vidant Paar says what's happening
between Afghanistan P Taliban and
Pakistan if both Afghanistan and
Pakistan are us proxies is it okay with
the us if these two
fight how does the Deep State benefit
from wars being fought worldwide okay
let's take the first question like one
question Afghanistan talian Pakistan so
where's the map here's the map quickly
take a look at the region um this is
Afghanistan
ancient gandhar this is Pakistan and
this is India bhat so yes uh Pakistan we
know is a is a longstanding US wasal US
asset us minion Bangladesh is a newly
minted us minion and Afghanistan is
currently uh it is being ruled by the
Taliban the Taliban came to power which
year 21 was it 2020 was it I don't
remember which year I'm sure it was 21
right not 22 21 and Afghanistan was
handed to the Taliban on a platter by
the
Americans and it at the time it was
being said that the Pakistani isi has
won and Afghanistan will become a
Pakistani wasal and pakist and and
Pakistan will get this what strategic
backyard in Afghanistan and I was the
one who was saying when this was
happening mark my mark my words Taliban
are going to be strongly strongly anti-
Pakistan and Pakistan will have their
hands full and I was Vindicated and I'm
still being Vindicated every single day
so Afghanistan and Pakistan are
essentially enemies today the Taliban
has no love for the
pakistanis
but allegedly Taliban is the US creature
which what what do I mean by that it is
alleged by very high ranking people who
have served in extremely high positions
in the Afghanistan government it is
being alleged by them that the Taliban
receives between 40 to 50 to 80 million
dollar a week in cash as a St depend
from the Americans and recently the
Americans by mistake sent like 340 or
$350 million or something something like
that some similar amount to the Taliban
by mistake apparently and the Americans
also left behind what 80 billion worth
of worth of arms and ammunition in
Afghanistan for the Taliban to use so
clearly the Taliban are to some extent
in some way or the other on the American
payroll to some extent now the Taliban
have no love for the Americans but they
will not say no to the cash and they
they came to some agreement Doha Accords
which has some secret Clauses as
well so the Taliban and the Americans
have some kind of understanding and
essentially the taliban's role is to
keep the Chinese out to a certain extent
and also to counterbalance Pakistan now
why would the Americans want two of
their wasal to be enemies is the
question isn't it does it make sense of
course it makes
sense look the Americans trust nobody
they understand how the world works the
American the US Empire is a continuation
of the British Empire they understand
they are Past Masters at ruling the
world divide and conquer divide and
rule the Americans don't trust the
Pakistani military even though the
Pakistani military has been their minion
there wasal for the past 70 or so years
the Americans know that these
generals and Military Officers are
treacherous and have no loyalty to
anyone if they can betray their own
country of course they'll bet the
Americans at the first opportunity so
how do you get the Pakistani military in
line by having a big stick outside of
Pakistan to beat them with which is the
Taliban okay so the deal is this
Pakistan and Bangladesh the two US vs
are there to counterbalance India
from the American perspective India
exists to counterbalance China so India
counterbalances China Pak East Pakistan
West Pakistan counterbalance
India and Afghanistan
counterbalances West Pakistan in case
the Pakistani military gets out of hand
you can use the Taliban to control them
and unleash whatever they want in in in
Pakistan that's the game that the
Americans are playing really really good
at the stuff the americ Americans we'll
admire
them hell says the US is trying to delay
our fighter aircraft projects by not
supplying engines on time of LCA thees
Mark 1 a and delaying the engine deal
for thees Mark 2 amca twin engine deck
based
fighter while Pakistan's Air Force
personnel have started training in the
Chinese j31 fifth generation fighter and
China already has 200 j50 j20 fifth
generation fighter planes our programs
have almost a decade left for induction
into our air force with unrealistic
timeline do you think we have already
lost our upper Edge over China as well
as Pakistan because we will because they
will get fifth generation Fighters
before us and should we participate in
the Su 57 program again okay a lot to
unpack here have we lost our upper Edge
over China we never had an upper edge
with China the Chinese Air Force was
always better than ours India should not
be but we we choose to be behind
everybody we have we we are supposed to
have 34 Air Force squadrons what's
what's the actual strength way below
that who is to blame for
this do does India lack in
money it's it's just it's just I mean
I'm short of words when it comes
to
describing the the
the the kind of strategic planning we
have so this is where we are now okay no
point going into the past and BL cling X
or Y or Z or whoever the hell here's
where they are the pakistanis will now
have the j20 j31 fifth generation
fighter theyve already started training
in that for the longest time they had
f-16s and at some point in time the f16s
were the best player in the world in the
region at least so they had this big
Edge over us we have what 36 raal and a
bunch of HJ podge of various kinds of
fighter planes we have our own Pages
Mark 1 a mark 2 Etc that we have
developing we need jet engines for them
we don't have an indigenous jet engine
we need the the American jet engines for
that the Americans are delaying the
order because they want to isue you know
put pressure on India to make us bend
the knee even more than we are bending
the knee right now they want India to be
a proper US vasal
state
complete vasal puppet that's what in the
the Americans want India to become okay
and we don't want that so what does
India do
one thing we could do is we could give
an order for 100 or 200 Rafal in case
the Rafal is a good enough fighter plane
it's a 4.5 generation fighter plane
perhaps not as good as a fifth
generation fighter but if in case it
suits our requirements we could give an
order for 100 or 200
Rafal we already know how to use the
thing we have we have been using it for
quite some time we are familiar with the
with the fire plane so we gave an order
for1 200 of these fighter planes and
with the caveat that since we are giving
such a gigantic order we're going to set
up the production line in India and we
produce these fighter planes in India so
that's good for our economy the
manufacturing and blah blah blah that's
one thing we could do but now the issue
remains that we still don't have an
indigenous jet engine and the
French are not entirely a Sovereign
Nation they come under nato in the EU
which means the Americans can apply
pressure on the French and create all
kinds of problems for India the other
option is the Russian sukko 57 fighter
plane yes is good one so the question is
how good is this fighter plane is it
good enough for us I'm sure it's a
fantastic fighter plane fifth generation
and so on but does
it suit our requirements we have very
specific requirements we have this very
specific geography very specific set of
adversaries is the suko 57 right for us
in case it is do the same thing
give an order for 100 or 200 or whatever
number of su 57s with the caveat that
we're going to produce them in India and
with the cave that you transfer jet
engine technology we have to acquire jet
engine technology some way or the other
buy beg borrow steel
whatever Roger Waters by big Bor
steel Eclipse anyhow um so and in the
meanwhile we have to keep on persevering
with the Cav program let it take another
10 20 years do doesn't matter keep on
doing it if you can or or if the current
Cav is is it has a reasonable amount of
thrust maybe 70 80 kons maybe 70 let's
say then why don't you design a twin
engine py the plane with two Cav engines
70 70 140 kons thrust as long as it can
do the After Burner thing properly so
I'm sure there are
solutions if you look at the Rafal it is
a twin engine fighter
plane and I'm pretty sure that the the
jet of the Rafal are kind of on par with
the cavari so why can't we do that sort
of thing I'm I'm sure there are it's not
as simple as I am making it sound but
we've got to find Solutions one of the
solutions is is to throw money either at
France or Russia I think with Russia
with France we have a reasonable amount
of understanding but France is
susceptible to American pressure we know
that it's not their fault but they are
Russia on the other hand may be
susceptible to some extent of Chinese
pressure so there are all these
considerations there are all these
considerations but if the suo 57 is
reasonably
good then we should get a whole bunch of
them while continuing to develop our own
indigenous fighter plates you know the
more the
merrier numbers quantity like the great
Joseph Stalin said quantity has a
quality of its own sorry quality
quantity has a quality of its own so you
may not have the best fighter planes in
the world but you if you have 2,000 of
them they're going to overwhelm your
enies so get a large number of fighter
planes as soon as
possible keep developing the pages one
Mark 1 a the mark 2 the AMC Advanced
medium combat aircraft the twin engine
deck based Fighter the aura gatak
whatever you call it and whatever else
you're developing whether people know it
or not keep on doing that keep
developing the Cav
engine but but as a stop Gap measure
acquire a certain number of fighter
planes from abroad if
required because we need numbers for
sure we need numbers and right now the
theas also has I don't know how many
production lines we are Ching out what
15 16 a year why can't we double that
but yeah that that's all kinds of
logistical problems and issues that
actually can be solved I'm sure so
that's how I see it the Americans will
obviously play every game in the book
they don't seek India to rise they don't
want India to rise they don't wish to
see India becoming a more powerful
Nation they want to curtail India's rise
and look from their perspective
obviously they would do that they don't
want a new China arising next 20 years
20 30 years from now they don't want
that to happen so they're not trying to
destroy India they're simply trying
to India's rise and that's that's
a logical thing to do from their
perspective so don't don't hate them
it's simply the the logic of strategy
that dictates they should do this so the
question is what do we do these are the
things we could do we should do either
get a whole bunch of raal or a whole
bunch of su 57s and don't try to Tinker
with the requirements okay we want that
feature this feature 78 more features
change this change that get whatever is
there get a whole bunch of those and
then develop your own plane that's what
we should do so tinkering of features
should be with your own indigenous
planes the foreign planes don't Tinker
too much get it as rapidly as possible
that's what I would say um learn from
the lessons of the past we've had so
many opportunities to to do these things
make it happen this time that's for our
would
say rra sarar says why didn't previous
Indian governments ever focus on
indigenous arms manufacturing despite
knowing the kind of fantastic
magnificent wonderful neighbor we have
and do you think we on the right path in
terms of Defense manufacturing I think
we are kind of on the right path uh the
Modi government has has made a
whole list of of Defense equipment that
we are not allowed to import anymore
which means we have to rely on
indigenous manufacturing which is great
which is fantastic it gives an impetus
to indigenous manufacturers and I'm I'm
sure we have good indigenous
manufacturers that's good uh there's so
much we can manufacture at home which
doesn't necessarily have to be very
Hightech so that is good why haven't
Indian past Indian governments focused
on indigenous arms manufacturing I don't
know who I was talking to recently we we
recently we have this fighter plane
right uh what's it
called I was speaking to a wing wing
Commander recently so we had the
marut the the Maru fighter plane
developed in the 60s 1960s by Kur tank
who was one of Germany's best aircraft
designers one of the world's best
aircraft designers so he designed this
marut fighter plane for us for India and
it flew it participated in I think the
71 War at least if not the 65 as well
but 71 definitely the problem with the
marut was that it was
underpowered its jet engines were not
powerful enough the design was
fantastic if we had acquired a better
set of jet engines and put them in the
fighter plane it would have been one of
the best in the world so we had that
fighter plane one of the best designs in
the
world and what do our military planners
do they kill the
project if we had continued the Maro
program and turn it into a family of
different kinds of aircraft then by
today we would have been one of the most
advanced manufacturers of f plan in the
world the the 1970s were what 50 55
years ago almost 55 years
ago so imagine what we could have
achieved in 50 years based on that one
initial design we could have iteratively
improved the design in a multitude of
different ways and come up with various
kinds of aircraft based on that one
design that's what we're doing right now
with the thees we're starting again from
scratch so why did this happen look why
do the
Pakistani why does the Pakistan
government their Nation
despite the having the option of not
ruining ruining the nation because they
don't care about the nation they are
beholden to themselves and to their
foreign
benefactors there are so many countries
in the world whose
governments
willingly sell off the nation's
sovereignty and resources to outside
forces
because the the the the core government
leaders have been bought
out lots of countries in Africa you know
these dictator dictatorships that are
that are propped up by the West in
Africa so many little nations with
dictators in in power and they will sell
off their country sovereignty resources
mineral wealth whatnot to foreign
nations in exchange for for whatever
they are
given uh Kickbacks whatever so you know
it is alleged that that's that's
something similar happened in India in
the
past you know what so buy buy our
equipment why do you have why do you
have to develop all this from scratch
such a difficult task we have this stuff
buy it from us and we'll give you 10% or
whatever perc allegedly that's how it
ised to work
allegedly so that's allegedly
why we are in the situation that we
allegedly are in allegedly
uh Sun Moon 0877 says will India attend
the SEO Summit in
Pakistan I could give you a long answer
but my answer is very straightforward
no uh RIT sarar says why did the
Vietnamese liberate Cambodia from the
hands of popot what were their interests
paulp was
this mad in insane person who killed I
don't know how many one to two to three
million of his own country people
completely innocent people my goodness a
as a kid I had The
Misfortune of of of seeing I was I was
sitting as a kid like a seven-year-old
or 8-year-old kid in a barber shop
waiting for snip snip snip and when you
sit in a barber shop it was in Europe so
I'm sitting in this Barber Shop waiting
for the barar to call me and in a barber
shop you have bunch of magazines right
all kinds of magazines so I open
magazine in this this coverage of
Vietnam oh sorry Cambodia the images my
goodness they seared In My Memory
horrible horrible no kid has to should
have to see that so this guy was a
monster brute brutal monster paulp he
was the leader of the Rouge the
redar thear were the Shay white
kingdom in which ruled over Cambodia
there were the red Kar the the Communist
Kar
and and they tried to destroy their
country's uh uh cultural and
civilizational Heritage they destroyed
temples Hindu temples Buddhist temples
they they killed
monks they all kinds of things and
obviously they they forced millions of
people into into uh um into agricultural
slavery and and I don't know how many
millions died two three million so that
was a situation now let's go to the map
okay and it's not far away from India
it's right here swabi east of swabi
Cambodia Vietnam so Cambodia is it's in
the 70s this is happening okay 75 76
around that time horrible horrible time
for Cambodia unimaginable Horrors were
perpetrated there and the K Rouge where
this so K rou who supported the K
rou it was the Chinese that supported
the k R and who supported Vietnam
another communist Nation the Soviets so
Vietnam was allied with the USSR and
Cambodia was Allied with
China in the 70s
was the time which comes after the the
soos Soviet split the CH so China and
the USS are no longer friends they're
kind of
enemies and the K Rouge were doing this
crossborder in incursions into Vietnam
and attacking Vietnam's Villages and
civilians and they k kill thousands and
thousands of Vietnamese
civilians and eventually Vietnam said
enough is enough and I think it is in 78
if I'm not mistaken
1978 the Vietnamese first of all they
sent fighter planes across the border to
strafe positions and then they sent the
Vietnamese Army and very rapidly overran
Karu positions in very various parts of
Cambodia and liberated Cambodia it was a
Liberation sent from the gods for the
people of Cambodia my God it ended the
reign of terror the horror of K rouj
rule so the Vietnam is liberated
Cambodia first of all because of the R's
repeated constant crossborder activity
they did not respect the the the the the
international border they did not
respect the sovereignty of Vietnam and
they were continually doing this crossb
incursions and encroaching on vietnames
territory
and it was being done allegedly at the
beh of
China so the Vietnamese then also knew
that the were perpetrating all these
horrific atrocities in Cambodia so that
gave them the moral High Ground to
launch this Invasion which they
characterized as a liberation of
Cambodia so that's how the Vietnamese
that's why the Vietnamese liberated
Cambodia from the hands of pulpot I
think it was in 78 78 or something this
happened 1978 and next year I think
February 29 the Chinese invaded
Vietnam to to punish the Vietnamese so
the Chinese invaded Vietnam from the
north from various parts
positions in the north so Vietnam and
and China have this
Border North of
Hanoi the Chinese people's Liberation
Army invades Vietnam very surprised
Invasion nobody expected and they've
rapidly make great progress and then the
Vietnamese Armed Forces
come into the picture and in a couple of
months the Chinese people's Liberation
Army is driven out and
defeated so that was the last actual war
that China was involved in it was a
humiliating defeat at the hands of
Vietnam all
right rudrajit sarar says again why did
Singapore leave
Malaysia okay in case we don't know
where it is Singapore Singapore Malaysia
once again not far from where we
are we have the state of malaka which
lies between Malaysia and Sumatra which
is in Indonesian the the westmost
Indonesian Island and at the very
southern tip of Malaysia we have
Singapore it's a city state essentially
so in the 60s
Etc um in the 60s uh Singapore
was a part of Malaysia it had joined
Malaysia I think in 63 or something 1963
please look up the exact dates I don't
remember dates I don't memorize dates
but Singapore was a part of Malaysia it
was called nagara Sing Sing singapur or
something nagar singapur or nagari
singapur or something like that so it
was there for a couple of years and then
Singapore was expelled out of Malaysia
PR out okay and I remember seeing a
video of leanu the founding father of
Singapore black and white video in which
he's actually shedding tears crying this
happened he was very very upset about
this so why did Singapore have to why
was Singapore expelled out of Malaysia
so this happened because of a variety of
differences political differences
economic differences as well as racial
tensions
between Malaysia and Singapore so uh the
political party of liwanu
joined uh Malaysia I think in
1963 but then the there were almost
immediately there were this political
differences and clashes with the with
the political party that was dominant in
Malaysia so the Malaysia the political
party that was ruling Malaysia at the
time they wanted
uh
privileges for the Malay people the
Malay Malay people they wanted a special
status for the Malay people so the Malay
people should be first class citizens
and everybody else especially Chinese
origin people should be second class
citizens Malay people should be the
first class citizens and Chinese origin
Indian origin other origin people should
be second class citizens and I'm sure
there's a religious angle also in there
I'm sure there was that and lean use
party wanted equality equal rights for
all citizens regardless of race religion
whatever leanu also wanted an open
economic model that's that's based on
free trade and Malaysia
wanted what he called
protectionist policies and Singapore
felt that it was not benefiting from
from the economic Union and that the
central government the Malaysian based
central government was restricting its
policies were restricting Singapore's
growth and then there was the the racial
angle Singapore's population was
predominantly Chinese and a significant
Indian origin population also and the
rest of the nation Malaysia was
dominated dominated by Malay people and
I think were there were riots that broke
out in
Singapore racial riots I think in a year
or so before Singapore was
expelled and that sort of thing so these
are the reasons why the the party and of
of Leu found it increasingly difficult
to deal with the ruling party in
Malaysia and these differences very
rapidly became
irreconcilable differences and then the
Malaysian prime minister essentially
expelled Singapore out of Malaysia and
Singapore became an independent
Sovereign Nation I am sure that this
process this this event was very
traumatic for leanu and the people of
Singapore but leanu then went ahead and
completely transformed Singapore in the
matter of just one generation roughly 20
years from a third world nation to a
first world country so that is a deal in
short kushagra
Kalashnikov what prevents India from
becoming the next warmonger heiman like
the US and China in the name of national
interest when we inevitably go super as
in super power if we hypothetically wear
the shoes of the Americans would we to
bomb innocent people and fund terrorist
organizations look there is no
inevitability to India becoming a
superpower it's not guaranteed please
understand this let's not be
overconfident I'm not sure if we even
want to be the kind of superpower the
Americans are having military bases all
over the world and having a multitude of
vasal states and doing regime change
operations and funding terrorism and
propping up of puet governments and
dictatorships do we want to do that but
so that's a question that's what the
question is about so if you want to
predict the future behavior of a
person the best way of being able to do
that is to look at their past Behavior
please understand that simple human
psychology if you have person X and you
want to know how what is this person
likely to do in the future what sort of
behavioral patterns can we expect from
this from this person in the future all
we have to do is look at the past of
this person what kind of past history
and record does a person have it's an
excellent indicator of how that person
will behave in the future similarly the
same goes for Nations and
civilizations Every Nation every
civilization every culture has a
personality in a set of traits
behavioral traits just like a human
being so we know how the Americans have
behaved the past
Century we know how China has
historically behaved especially after
the the Chinese Communist party to cover
right 1949 or
thereabouts now the question is the
question kushagra is asking is that if
hypothetically India becomes a great
power superp power if hypothetically we
are in the shoes of the Americans which
means we are superpower would India too
start bombing Innocents like what they
did in Malay in in Vietnam Laos Iraq
Libya Etc would India also bomb
innocence would India also fund
terrorists like the American funded
Pakistani terrorism and all that would
India also do that all you have to do to
answer the question is look at India's
past now India has a rather lengthy
past 10,000 years roughly of which we
have a very good understanding of at
least the past two and a half 3,000
years and decent understanding of the
past 5 6,000 years the Saras Hindu era
period phase of Indian
history we also know that Indians have
actually in the past ruled over foreign
lands it is known and I can give you
evidence of that so once again we go to
the map okay you go westwards and you
come to Syria and Anatolia here you had
the kingdom of the mitani and the
kingdom of the
hittite which the mitan when did the
rule about 17 or 1800 BC they started
ruling in this region and until 1500 or
so BC they were ruling as a kingdom the
miani the mitani ruling class or
aristocra aristocracy spoke Sanskrit
late Vic srit how do we know this there
is evidence of that um so there is
what's the evidence there is a peace
treaty between the mitani and the
Hittites these two neighboring kingdoms
they had some differences and some
disagreements which probably led to some
some uh Warfare or whatever and then
there is a peace treaty
H at Bas
Cal and that peace treaty was written
down in an inscription and the uniform
script between the two
kingdoms and in this peace treaty a
number of gods are invoked as Witnesses
for sealing and binding the
treaty who are these
Gods Mitra varuna the Ashwin
Twins and Indra
so these gods were invoked from by both
sides the mitani and the Hittites what
does it tell you that the ruling class
of both these nations or
kingdoms worship these Gods now these
gods are Vic
Gods which tells you that the ruling
class of both these nations or or
kingdoms was Indians and we know that
the mitani ruling class aristocracy they
spoke Sanskrit late W
srit so this inscription is an Evidence
of that and then you have the horse
training man ual of a guy called Kuli
Kuli the horse master who who trained
war horses and he wrote a detailed
manual on How to Train War hor horses
that manual you can still implement it
today and you will get extremely well
trained war horses battle horses so this
manual Kuli wrote this manual in the
local huran
language but unfortunately there in the
local hurrian language you could not
express certain Technical and scientific
terms so for those terms he Kuli had to
use his mother tongue which was vidc
Sanskrit so that is the first actual
inscription inscriptional evidence we
have of Vic late Vic srit anywhere in
the world the oldest about 15 1500 BC
actual written inscriptional
evidence but note this that Kuli wrote
the text in the local huan
language and also note that most of the
gods that were invoked and praised by
this Kingdom were the local hurrian
Gods but when the peace treaty happened
between the two kingdoms it was the Vic
Gods because both the aristocratic
classes ruling classes were of Indian
origin so what it tells you is that
these Indians who ruled over this far
off land they tried their best to write
in the local language and to honor the
local gods and
Customs they were not colonialists they
did not impose their religion on the
natives they did not impose their way of
life and their language on the
natives
that's Indian culture that's what we are
like so we have in the past ruled over
various kingdoms Central Asia Syria
Anatolia various parts of the world
Indian origin King Kingdoms in Southeast
Asia at also we have never been
colonialists we have never been settler
colonialist we have never been
extractors of wealth and resources we
have never been imperialists we've never
been
hedonists we have never imposed our way
of life and culture and religion and
language Etc on others we have
assimilated so we will behave in the
future also in our own way we will not
bomb Innocents we will not fund
terrorists that's not our way but we may
still
rise yeah if the gods so
will and if we please the gods with our
actions okay Karishma says Tibetan
Buddhists talk a lot lot about a great
Indian pundi called Padma Samba how old
are the cultural linkages between India
and Tibet interesting question padas
Samba Guru Rino Rino so Guru Rino also
called padmamba was a great great Indian
spiritual Buddhist Guru who dates back
to the I believe 8th Century
ad which is 700 something whatever ad
okay look up the exact dates I'm sure
you'll find them um and he apparently
was born in a kingdom called
udana so we're not quite sure where
Odana is today because we know no longer
use the name Odana but it is said it is
believed it was
suu which is currently called SWAT SWAT
Valley in in currently temporarily in
Pakistan where is
SWAT come on man
SWAT uh kber okay SWAT Pakistan so here
okay over
here so this is suu historical suu and
now called swap
and possibly this could be the Odana
Kingdom so in case that is true that
Odana is today Su or SWAT then
padmasambhava Guru padmamba was born in
this region the northwest of India and
he was a tremendously accomplished
highly accomplished uh spiritual Master
a great Guru of
Buddhism and he was requested to to come
and uh visit Tibet and come and live in
Tibet and teach the Tibetan people
Buddhism so he did that he traveled to
Tibet and he became the great Guru Rino
the original great teacher of Buddhism
the oldest school of Buddhism that is
that the Tibetans have and uh so that's
about him and and his consort was a
great Tibetan lady also a great great
highly accomplished spiritual Guru
herself I forget her name but yeah that
is that is there is a story of padmamba
or or Guru
Rin now that is not clearly not the
beginning of the of the linkages
cultural Etc between bhat and bhesh
which is
Tibet uh look we've had this tradition
for thousands of years of going to this
region on
pilgrimages there are there's this
incredibly
uh important Lake
in
Tibet okay it's called Manas over today
you have Chinese
names
uh okay maner is
here so they call it Ma mang whatever
whatever Chinese name they have imposed
on it that is a temporary thing but this
is one of the this is probably one of
the most sacred lakes in in Indian
culture and civilization and it is next
to a lake called rakas
and north of it obviously we have the
great Mount Kash and all of this is in
Tibet and we have been going there on
pilgrimage our ancestors have been going
there for thousands of years long before
Buddhism or Lord Buddha go Shri gutam
Buddha even existed so the cultural
linkages go go back thousands of years
thousands and thousands of years but
yeah so to make a long story short there
is a story of of Guru ruch or pmaa the
the the the the guru who
brought uh B the Dharma into Tibet and
essentially
transformed the The Fortunes of
Tibet okay we have a tremendously long
question here but I'm sure it's very
important so I'll take it I'm currently
in my first year of the baf degree
program not sure what that is but okay
which is as per the new education policy
2020 which includes I as a subject
Indian knowledge systems in one of the
ik classes the professor was teaching a
topic in which she mentioned or talked
about the Arian Invasion Theory and its
connection with the Indo European
languages stating these languages
originated due to the Arian Invasion
Theory however the invasion theory is
not proven and could be considered fake
it's concerning that this information is
being shared without acknowledging or
knowing that it's not proven I think
many professors themselves don't know
that it's not proven or fake or its
disputed nature they're ignorant about
this status many students will get
incorrect information about it and then
they will perceive it as being the truth
yes and you are right you know people
ask me why do I criticize the new
education policy why do I say that it's
like applying a bandage on a gunshot
wound why do I say such things why am I
negative here you have it here you have
it it's not enough to give a new name
and make some cosmetic
changes in the education
system what matters is the outcome
are we getting the right outcome what is
the purpose of Education what are we
trying to achieve through the education
system nothing changes you can fiddle
around and make make cosmetic changes
and give a new fancy name new education
policy but the content Remains the Same
then what's the point of this entire
exercise except wasting of time Indian
knowledge systems and in Indian
knowledge systems you're teaching the
Arian Invasion myth as if it's a
fact this is the problem and I you know
there are lots of well-meaning
teachers I have been pretty harshly
critical about the quality of teachers
haven't
I well that criticism is not unfounded
but I am sure there are good teachers as
well I I remember as a kid I had one or
two good teachers who I still remember
fondly one or two most were
obal so even if you are a good teacher
and you
are a well-meaning
person but as long as you even then if
you're not aware of the truth then
you're going to teach incorrect
information to the
kids so it's possible that these
professors themselves don't know that
this theory is is unproven it's
actually untrue it's a myth it's a
myth and why do they not know it because
they don't
try to update their knowledge they have
no interest in
research so that kind of tells you the
story of the quality of the Indian
teachers um so yeah that is a sad state
of the Indian education system the new
education policy is doing nothing of any
any use to us I'm extremely disappointed
in how things are going uh we've had 10
years the Modi government has has had 10
years to change things but they have not
changed things they've come up with this
wonderful new name new education policy
which does nothing actually which makes
no real change it has no change on the
outcomes we still taught the same old
garbage which is disappointing I don't
mean to be all cynical and negative okay
the Modi government has done a
tremendous amount of good work as well
but I am disappointed
because look obviously Mr Modi can't
handle everything and neither should be
should he be expected to but you have
Ministries for everything for each indiv
idual thing you have a minister and you
have Ministers of state right what are
they doing what is the ministry of
culture doing what is the ministry of
Tourism doing what is the education
Ministry doing they are doing nothing
other Ministries are doing fantastic I'm
sure but these several Ministries I am
extremely disappointed with their
performance and at the end of the day
their boss should hold them to account
and it's not happening so
disappointing Kush Kalashnikov says
cultural appropriation what are your
views on it is it really offensive for
let's say a white man to wear a turban
if they're not making fun of it I
personally don't think so I'm asking you
this because in your speech at the world
Hindu Congress in Bangkok you said that
the West has appropriated yoga okay
interesting point that you make if a
white man or a non-indian person wants
to wear a turban and he's doing it in a
respectful manner not trying to make fun
of it is it
offensive I don't think
so if you're not making fun of my
culture and you're trying something out
I have no objection I have no issue I
don't find it offensive okay that's my
answer to the first part of your
question if a foreign lady wants to wear
a sar why should I find it offensive let
her wear it let her be
happy good for
her let more of them do it I have
absolutely no issue with that that is
not cultural appropriation
okay that is not cultural appropriation
what is cultural appropriation let's try
and see what the dictionary has to say
about this term appropriation shall we
maybe that will give us a hint
appropriation what does it
mean the act of appropriating or taking
possession of something often without
permission or consent
anything appropriate for special purpose
especially money and so on so forth okay
so that is
appropriation essentially it is
theft okay it's essentially
theft now let's let's dive a little
deeper into cultural
appropriation so when when is cultural
appropriation of
problem a foreign person wearing a sar
wearing a turban wearing an Indian dress
trying to speak an Indian language I
have no objection to it I have no
problem with it because they are doing
it out of their own interest and they're
not being disrespectful but when it
comes to
yoga instead of giving you words let me
give you pictures shall I let us go back
to Google
H uh yoga so I have no issue with the
fact that if you go to Google Images you
will find mostly non-indian people doing
yoga that's fine my problem is with
this what is hot
yoga there is no such thing as hot yoga
but these individuals are doing
something called Hot Yoga what is drunk
yoga there is something called drunk
yoga look at that yoga and wine yoga and
beer yoga and God knows what
else what is Power Yoga there is no such
thing as Power Yoga but they have
created something called Power Yoga what
is dog
yoga they doing yoga with
dogs okay does Indian culture tradition
have yoga with dogs we don't but these
people have invented dog yoga what is
goat
yoga well there is yoga with goats you
see when you distort when you take my
culture and distort it that's a problem
for me that is cultural theft that is
cultural appropriation when
when
This Bitter cynical person takes
pranayam and takes the practices of
Himalayan yogis who spend years in the
snow he combines that together and calls
it the wiim Hof method that is cultural
theft he has stolen these ideas and pass
them off as his own invention his own
creation the Wim Hof method
it is
Basta you know the the it's a technique
in in in pranayam bastri that's what he
uses and he also uh Advocates cold cold
water immersion and and exposure to cold
temperatures all of that has been
practiced for thousands of years by
Indians and he has simply combin two of
these or three of these things together
and he's he's passing it off as the Wim
Hoff method and he has become a great
celebrity
yog guys is about joy
happiness Etc does that guy look happy
to you have you seen his face how angry
how bitter he is at all times that is
cultural theft that's cultural
appropriation cultural appropriation is
when a guy like Andrew huberman takes
Indian practices and gives them western
names cardiac coherence breathing huh
what is cardiac coherence breathing it
is a madeup name for pranayam that's
what people like Andrew hubman do so
this is what I mean by cultural cultural
appropriation I have no problem with
westerners or anybody in the world
practicing yoga but when they take yoga
and distort it out of proportion and and
and and distorted in a tremendously
disrespectful way that's what I have a
problem with I hope it makes sense what
I'm
saying geopolitical duas say can we call
TM Shinto and zer trism non bhara
dharmic culture look the origins are not
dhic but the the these religions the
this these this these cultures have
significant polytheistic traits that are
very similar to to dhic culture so
theism has a Pantheon of gods and
goddesses there is the sky father thingi
there is the Earth Mother umai and there
is a whole Pantheon of other gods and
goddesses there are elements of nature
worship Spirit Worship Forest worship
the spirit of the forest U ancestor
worship and so much more so it's it's
very polytheistic and from that
perspective you can consider it to be
very similar to dhic uh culture Shinto
very
similar we have in Shinto you have Kami
which are spirits various kinds of Kami
your ancestors spirits of the forest
same kind of
thing and and so on so once again it's
very polyes that's why Shinto
syncretized so naturally with both the
Dharma and Hinduism which came in from
India and then you had very distinctive
syncretic Japanese culture mainly which
was mainly Shinto and the dharmic
elements Hinduism Buddhism every single
Hindu god and goddess is represented in
Shinto today in in Japan today but it's
not exactly dharmic culture it is
distinctively Japanese so it is I would
not call it non- bharatia dharmic
culture I would say that it's it's
almost 100% compatible with dhic culture
but it is definitely not non bhara is it
dharmic well dharmic is what originates
in India so not dharmic from the
perspective but 100% dharmic compatible
zor aism you know zaratustra
zatra he was born somewhere in gandhar
maybe maybe her maybe bul somewhere
there or maybe Northeastern Iran
Persia and he in
inverted Hindu Dharma he inverted the
the dhic faith the the
dharmic pantheon of gods so he turned
the asuras see in the
Vic
perspective there are the theas and the
asuras right the dasas are kind of the
good guys the asuras is kind of the
naughty guys not exactly demons or evil
but kind of slightly negative perception
of the asuras and more positive
perception of the dasas overall right
the danavas were asuras right danavas
danavas were rather naughty people they
did naughty stuff and they were expelled
out of India they ended up in Ireland
anyhow so um in the Vic perception the
asuras are the slightly bad guys the the
the dasas are the slightly Good Guys
Zoro zaratustra inverted that he turned
the dasas into the bad guys and the
asuras into the good guys so that is not
very dharmic that is kind of adharmic to
do that he inverted the morality the
Moral Moral
perception you could regard it as as as
a rebellion against Hinduism whatever
but it remained a very much a
polytheistic
religion and uh yeah so I would not call
it dhic
Zoroastrianism definitely not dharmic
but it had many from most of the dharmic
elements in a
slightly
inverted all right
uh sea says what are your thoughts on
the dark Triad in
Psychology and why do I feel like these
are the traits that most of the
governments across the world especially
in the collective West are embracing
without any remorse or responsibility
for their actions but acting almost like
an
entity where is this world heading
towards so what is this dark Triad in
Psychology interesting to get a question
about psychology but psychology is is
very
relevant uh strangely enough to
geopolitics and history because it's
it's human psychology that that drives
the world isn't it whether it's
individual human psychology or or
Collective psychology it's psychology
that drives the world human needs wants
desires
ambition characteristics personality
traits and so on so what is this dark
Triad so in Psychology there's this Trio
of negative personality traits
one of these traits is
narcissism the other is
melanism MAV melanism and the third is
psychopathy so these out of these I
think psychopathy is the is the worst
psychopathy means
you consider other people of to be of no
worth and you are only concerned about
yourself and you see other people as
tools to be used and
manipulated so that's psychopathy uh
narcissism is about having an inflated
super inflated opinion of yourself and
having maybe no empathy and once again
not seeing any value in other people and
and seeing other people as tools to be
used so that's narcissism and melanism
is about you cannot be maavan without
having a high IQ without without being
highly intelligent but once again it's
all about ulating and using people so
these are the three negative personality
traits the dark
Triad and uh generally people who score
highly on on these three personality
traits they are very likely to cause
social problems
and manipulate and use other people and
commit crimes and so on and
interestingly like you say it's possible
that many of the world leaders today
could score highly on the dark trial
especially like you're saying in the
collective West well I will leave it to
my viewers to judge
whether many of these leaders in the
collective West exhibit these traits
maybe you can zero in on one specific
leader and ask yourself does this person
have any of these personality traits
narcissism psychopathy
melanism
Etc but yeah yeah you can kind of see
the collective West kind of behaving in
that fashion you know ever since the age
of colonialism started that kind of is
that isn't it
uh considering other other other
cultures of other nations as having no
value using them regarding them as
as resources to be extracted regarding
the whole planet as a resource to be
plundered and
extracted um not valuing the human life
of of people of other nations and other
cultures and so on that is kind of very
much within the ballpark of the dark
Triad so yes I definitely agree with
what you are saying and I would rather
not dig deeper into it because then you
will come up with invariably come up
with the deeper underlying religious and
cultural aspect of
it
okay is it possible to ACH achieve
greatest things even if you're not a
child prodigy I think I should achieve
great things and I'm willing to put
everything into it to achieve it but I'm
not a child Pro prod like Terence Tow
and I'm already 20 years old it's
interesting you speak about Terence tow
because I referenced a couple of his
books yesterday so teren Stow in case
you're not
aware just
FYI Terren St was this is this just
genius level mathematician Fields Medal
winner
okay
um he was a child prodigy you will see
him with Eros Paul
Eros look at him Paul OS is one of the
great mathematicians and you can see him
with teren star when when teren STW was
I don't know eight seven eight nine
years
old and Terren STW went on to win the
fields medal and is one of the greatest
mathematicians alive today so that's
teren T and he clearly was a child
prodig but you don't have to be a child
prodigy to to do great things in
life most of the people who have
tremendous accomplishments in their
lifetime most of them don't start out as
child prodiges okay um so it's fine if
you have not been a child prodigy that's
fine and 20 years is just like the
beginning of Life I think that's where
you start out in life you're hopefully
done with the education system that time
that wastage of time is over now we can
go out in the world and do stuff so look
life is long you with today's technology
and medical science advancements Etc you
can be definitely productive until you
in your 80s for sure see just starting
off so be
positive and maybe you will discover the
greatness in yourself going forward
maybe the education system was what was
hampering you it's very possible very
possible so it is definitely the answer
is yes it is definitely possible to
achieve the greatest of things even if
you're not a child prodigy okay go out
there do your best put in the greatest
of efforts and I'm sure you will do well
and I'm sure you'll do great things okay
all the
best okay Malik Sayad says can you help
us all by suggesting some tips for
studying calculus and neutronian physics
at the entrance exam level
IIT also how can we stay focused on
study as we know that this education
system is just a waste but we also need
to fulfill the TR traditional education
method to get ree in top universities
this lead us to get our time wasting on
other useless things okay first of all
how do you uh study calculus in neonian
phys very simple the right way to study
calculus to study Physics neutronian
physics is to solve problems the
concepts are very few the concepts are
easy to understand but how do you
internalize those concepts by
solving tons of problem s so how do you
do it very simple so let
me let me show you exactly how to do it
where do you find these problems to
solve in calculus for example let's
start with Calculus let's go to
Amazon simple CH
calculus the best book of all time if
you want problems to solve um this one
Tom's outline of calculus I don't know
which Edition is best but the seventh we
should do 592 Pages it has okay let's
let's try and take a look inside and
let's take a look at the table of
contents does it have everything you
need so it starts with a very Basics
linear coordinate systems rectangular
systems lines circles equations and the
graphs functions limits continuity the
derivative rules for differentiating
functions implicit differentiation
tangents etc etc maximum minimum Maxima
minimum C sketching trigonometry
trigonometric functions inverse
functions rect linear Etc related rates
then you come to differentials Newton
anti-derivatives which is the integral
definite integral fundamental the of
calculus natural logarithm etc etc lal's
rule uh volume integration integration
the paths uh techniques of integration
of various kinds improper Integrations
as you can see it's got everything you
want in calculus plane vectors curve
linear motion polar coordinates infinite
sequences and series Power series Taylor
McLaren series partial derivatives it's
got everything where is okay vector
differentiation integration where is the
differential equations it has a very
brief section on differential equations
so you may not get differential
equations practice from here for that
you go to ten bomb and polard Tenon bomb
polard so this is the book you use for
differential equations it's it's sitting
right behind me somewhere here you do
that book that's it you're done so
that's the only two books you need to
master calculus for whatever exam
for whatever exam and obviously for the
i j you need to have those question
papers of previous years you see the
format of questions but to be a master
of calculus that's the only two books
you need the Sha series book and tenan
bomb and polard which is this book over
here you see this book here that's the
one and what about
uh what what about physics right or
Newtonian physics well let me show you
Newtonian physics that's two good books
for that one is klepner and
col co
co that's a good uh bachelor's degree
level to level of book okay introduction
to mechanics superb books as you can see
very good rating that's a great book and
if you want to go slightly beyond that
you go mechanics
Morin so yeah this one introduction to
classical mechan this is a more detailed
introduction more involved introduction
another brilliant book that's the only
two books you need and if you want to
solve lots of problems I'm sure there is
Sha's theoretical mechanics so my point
is to genuinely become master of either
calculus or Newtonian mechanics you have
to first comprehend very quickly the the
fundamentals the main principles and
then
solve a bus load a truckload of problems
as many problems as you can by solving
problems you internalize I those
patterns and regularities and rules
that's what you do that's what I can say
then how do you stay focused on study if
you want to do great things you have to
tell yourself that I have to go through
this pain to achieve great things so
that's how you motivate
yourself all the best all of
you uh how did life first appear on
Earth how did life first appear on Earth
so look the universe is 13.8 billion
years old roughly our solar system is
4.6 roughly billion years old the Earth
is about 4.5 billion years old and life
appears on Earth about 3.8 billion years
before today roughly approximately plus
or minus whatever so life appears on
Earth and then life proliferates on
Earth and it and then we end up with us
very complicated complex human beings
now what is the common thing in life
what do all life forms on our planet
whether they viruses or bacteria or
birds or octopuses or humans or
chimpanzees or gorillas or donkeys or
whatever fishes what do all of them have
in common they have something in common
all of them despite being so different
DNA the genetic code The
genome the blueprint for life so the
genome is is the blueprint of how to
create proteins how proteins are created
proteins are this incredibly complex
molecules that are the the the the basis
and the fundamental of Life your muscle
and muscles everything is made of
proteins so the DNA genome is the
blueprint of how to code those proteins
and without proteins you can't have DNA
it's kind of interconnected now the
Genome of human beings is quite
complicated it's about twice as large as
as the Genome of fish the Genome of fish
is twice as large as the Genome of a
worm let's say the Genome of a worm is
about I don't know
so so it is believed that it is it is
observed
that the size of the genome doubles
roughly every 300 or 500 million years
maybe 300 million
years so if we go back in
time and we want to arrive at the
simplest possible genome you would have
to go back roughly 10 billion
years to arrive at the very fundamental
simplest
genome with just a few base
pairs but we
our planet is only 4.5 billion years old
and life originated only 3.8 billion
years
ago but to come to arrive at the most
fundamental kind of genome you have to
go back about 10 billion years how does
that work makes no sense so it looks
like life appeared on Earth rather well
Advanced and well formed with a rather
complex genome in the the most fun
fundamental fundamental BL
organisms which is weird which is very
weird so how could one explain that that
the first genome that appeared on Earth
was already well made and pretty
complex it did not have the
time to evolve into that that that much
of a complex thing so how did it evolve
obviously Evolution must have
happened so the answer is maybe maybe
life evolved outside our planet
H how what were conditions like 10
billion years before today the universe
was very different it was much smaller
much hotter than it is
today right now the average temperature
of inter Stellar space is about 2.7
degrees
Kelvin sorry 2.7 Kelvin what on Earth am
I saying not degrees Kelvin 2.7 Kelvin
roughly roughly that's the temperature
of the average Cosmic
wave uh tmbr Photon Cosmic microwave
background radiation Photon but in the
past it was much warmer so there was a
time after the big bang when the
temperature of interstellar
space was precisely in the goldilock
zone
between 4 to 100°
C the temperature range in which water
is liquid there was a time period
okay when the universe's average
temperature was that which means that
liquid water just naturally would have
occurred in
space and maybe it's then that the first
life the first DNA
molecules somehow um evolved over
millions tens of millions hundreds of
millions billions of years and because
life could just appear in space in inter
space so that's why this this genetic
material was seeded everywhere in the
universe because the universe was much
smaller than on asteroids on space dust
on God knows what else and maybe this
these Seeds of Life have been drifting
all across the cosmos for billions of
years and maybe after our planet was
formed maybe there was an impact of an
asteroid which carried this blue plant
of life already reasonably well
developed and that's how life was seeded
on Earth maybe that is how it happened
do we have evidence of this absolutely
none does it make sense scientifically
yes it does it's a plausible theory of
which we have no evidence thus far maybe
we will never have evidence of this far
but the question is there that how did a
highly Advanced genome appear on earth
when we know that the genome size
doubles once in every 300 or so million
years so if you go back 3.8 billion
years we come up with a very large
genome not a very rudimentary
fundamental genome so to arrive at that
you to go back about 10 billion years
which makes no sense unless life
actually originated outside our planet
in the Deep Antiquity of our universe
even before the sun itself was
born okay BoJack Horseman 9 says can we
reach type 1 civilization on the kadashi
scale by 2100 are we reaching there
under one world government or few
Advanced Nations will reach there first
I think it's beli that we are about 2.
seven something on sorry 0.7 something
on the kardashev scale what is the
kardashev
scale a
Russian uh cosmologist scientist
astronomer whatever he was asist
kardashev he came up with this
classification scale on this scale a
civilization that is a type one
civilization on on the C scale is a
civilization that is capable of
harnessing and utilizing and capturing
the entire energy of its home planet
which means means it's able to control
earthquakes and volcano and everything
all of that wind everything is it's able
to control and harness so we clearly
aren't there we are not type one type
two means a civilization that can
harness and control the entire energy
output of its host
star so it's like Humanity being able to
control and and completely capture the
energy output of the sun that's type two
and type three means you can do it for
the whole galaxy that's type 1 two three
in on the kardashi scale we are not at
type one yet we are 0.7 something I
think there was a paper recently by some
Chinese
scientists let me try and see it's in
nature
right let me put that on the screen
kardashev one second okay so there what
does it
say let's quickly take a look scientific
reports nature forecasting the
progression of human civilization on the
kardashi scale through 2060 with a
machine learning approach Jang Yang Lu
and
fun so it says that Humanity presently
stands at type 0.727 six on the Kash
scale and blah blah blah blah blah
and this paper suggest that Global
energy consumption is expected to reach
8887 ajs in 2060 so in 2060 Humanity
will be at 7. 0.744 n civilization which
is not a very big Leap Forward
definitely not closer to
1.0 so that's what this paper suggests
it says that by 2060 we'll we have a
incremental slight
Improvement progression so what do I
think can we reach type one by 2100 I
think it's unlikely
unless we
develop artificial super intelligence in
which case we could become very rapidly
a type 1 civilization Pro possibly by
2100 so in case AI becomes super
intelligent and we achieve artificial
super intelligence which is One Step
Beyond artificial general intelligence
if if that happens if ASI happens then
we could quickly become a type one
civilization under a One World
Government only in that case otherwise
it's
unlikely okay manik says if Earth is 13
billion years old what okay if the Earth
is 13 billion years old how can red of
stars exist for trillions of years okay
it's not the Earth that's 13 billion
years old it's the
universe that's about 13.8 billion years
old and the question is about red
dwarves how could red dwarfs exist for
trillions of years when the universe
itself is 13.8 billion years old good
question I like
it no problem with it so let's take a
look at what red wolves are what is a
red dwarfes let's let's go to our friend
Google and ask and and try and visualize
is a red dwarf shall we it's the
smallest kind of main sequence star Red
Dwarf a red WF star is the smallest what
on Earth is this I don't know what that
is it's some Sci-Fi
series it's the smallest type of of main
sequence
star
um so um so it's it's a star that's red
in color okay red in in a very small
it's typically 0.01 or 0.02 times the
mass of the Sun approximately that's
that's the kind of star it is now what's
the deal with red dwarf that's the
question how can it exist for trillions
of years so here's
how red wolf Stars can exist for
trillions of years it's because of
their significantly low mass and very
efficient usage of energy what's energy
we'll come into that so first of all
these stars are generally
about 0.1 to 0.5 0.6 times the mass of
the Sun significantly smaller maybe 10%
of the size of the sun to half the size
of the sun roughly that sort of uh Mass
range red dwarves have so they the
smallest and coolest type of main
sequence star and because they are so
small the temperatures in their core are
very low about 3,000 to 4,000 Kelvin
which means that they burn through their
fuel nuclear fuel hydrogen way slower
than larger stars like the Sun so the
nuclear fuel in stars is hydrogen mainly
hydrogen most of it is hydrogen and how
is it burned it's not burned it's fused
into helium Fusion nuclear fusion so if
you want to see nuclear fusion reactions
look at the sun I mean don't look at it
directly but that's that's what's
happening okay so these stars are are
much smaller and much cooler the cores
are much cooler so so they burn through
the nuclear fuel much slowly much slower
than stars like the sun and there is
convection full convection of the
internal part the the the interior of
these of these stars because they're
much smaller and much cooler so
the the interior of the star can be
thought of as as a hot liquid not a gas
hot liquid and there is complete
convection which means that everything
is properly mixed inside in the case of
larger and hotter stars there is not
full convection not complete convection
which means there
is impart improper or incomplete mixing
of the internal gases of of a star like
the Sun so uh that's why um red dwarfs
are able to fuse all of their hydrogen
in in the case of sun stars like the sun
only the hydrogen in the core is fused
other hydrogen is not used until much
later that sort of thing so the fusion
process is much smaller it happens at a
much slower Pace because of the coolness
of the star the hydrogen even though
it's less it is burned at a very slow
rate compared to larger stars and that
is what expands the lifespan of red
dwarves
significantly so because these Stars
Burn hydrogen so slowly and so
efficiently their lifespans are
essentially tens of billions of years or
even trillions of years
now the current age of the universe is
13. 8 billion years so how can a red
dwarf have a lifespan of a trillion
years all it all it means is that when
the universe is a trillion years old
these red dwarfs will still be around
they will not have disappeared they will
not have died that's what it means and
so essentially not a single red dwarf
that has ever been born in the universe
has until today exhausted its hydrogen
fuel so every dwarf that was born in the
universe still exists they will keep on
existing for tens of billions of years
or or or even trillions of years and
like other like certain other kinds of
stars which die which end their life in
in the Supernova explosion red dwarfs
don't undergo a supernova explosion they
simply quietly slowly gradually cool
down cool down from a red dwarf they'll
become a white dwarf and then eventually
they'll become a black dwarf that is
what happen Happ s to Red dwarfs that is
the eventual fate of a red dwarf
star all right with that I am at the
end of today's uh of the questions I
selected let me take some questions from
the live
chat uh okay let's see this surj says
please answer my questions what do you
think really happened at the World Trade
cental
911 why is the US not commenting on the
Brazilian dictatorial president and
Supreme Court Judge look El musk is
talking about the the president in
Brazil he's calling that guy a dictator
he's calling the Supreme Court Judge a
dictator Etc so Elon Musk is doing it
the US government doesn't have to do it
what really happened the World Trade
Center
911 I don't
know I don't know what happened some
things not quite don't quite make sense
but yeah yeah so I know where you're
coming from but I don't have the
answers best not to have answers to such
questions you
know
uh okay shasat mukarji says how did the
dollar become the world's Reserve
currency long that's a very involved
long answer to give but I'll give you a
very brief version of the answer the
Britain Woods conference
1944 was was held in the Britain Woods
hotel somewhere in the US all the major
economies of the world were present
there the Americans were on the verge of
winning the second world war they not
yet tested nuclear weapons on Japan it
was going to happen so the writing was
on the wall Germany was going to lose
Japan was going to lose the Americans
were the big winners of the first of the
second world war and they were now going
to impose their hemony On The World by
making the US dollar the world's Reserve
currency so this
agreement happened at the Britain Woods
hotel it's called the Britain Woods
agreement which made it official that
the US dollar would be the world's
Reserve currency it would be pegged to
the price of gold which the us then
later on went back back on during the
time of President Nixon so that's how
the dollar became the world's Reserve
currency
um okay per 444 says the UK went from
the world's number one hedgman to a
failed state will the US follow well the
UK isn't quite a failed state right
Pakistan is a failed State Somalia to
some extent is a failed State the US the
UK isn't a failed State it's still
functions reasonably well it is mostly a
rather poor nation that is attached
to London which is the world's Center
for moneya
laundering and uh yeah but it it lost
its first class geopolitical status it
it it seized to be a first class
geopolitical power around 1956 1958 the
Su crisis time period um so all empires
have this this phase right they are
born they rise they ascend they reach
their Pinnacle and then they decline in
the fall and they eventually disappear
every Empire goes through this cycle the
Imperial cycle some Empires rise
multiple times okay that also
happens um will the US follow every
Empire follows this so no Empire lasts
forever generally a a good Empire a
powerful Empire generally lasts about 2
300 years maybe 400 years at most 500
years the Mori Empire what 300 years
roughly 250 300 years the Roman Empire
500 years at most at the the peak of its
power it was about 200 300 years uh and
many other Empires the Mongol Empire not
even 200 years the British Empire 2 250
years the US Empire begins let's say
around the 1940s so let's see how long
it lasts okay it's a cyclic process and
the US Empire essentially is a
continuation of of the British Empire it
just took
over the work of the British Empire it
just the British Empire handed the beton
to the Americans so it's a continuation
of the same entity essentially which
would give it a significantly longer
time period but let's see how long it
lasts so nothing lasts forever no Empire
lasts forever eventually every Empire
does decline and fall when will it
happen can't really tell can't say
okay
um goam Arian RI says China is facing a
demographic disaster uh your thoughts on
robots and AI replacing the workforce
and soldiers in 30 years due to
technology as we've already seen
cost-effective drones changing War a
technology is going to play a
significant very major uh role in
Warfare in the economy in everything
going
forward uh very soon you will have very
Advanced robotics which means that most
manual intervention in factories
assembly lines will will disappear and
everything will be automated everything
will be robotic right and AI will do a
lot of lot of the work as well so China
is indeed like you correctly say facing
a demographic disaster uh the total
fertility rate in China has dropped to
1.1 almost 1.0 which is is a catastrophe
like I've said a thousand times before
and China is going to get old very fast
the average median age of the population
will will be in the 40s 50s even 60s
soon enough so China is
following the same path as
Japan and there's nothing they can do
about this right now no matter what they
do it's going to happen so then it is
said that the Chinese will then leverage
AI artificial intelligence they will
leverage their their expert
in industry in in in robotics Etc to
offset the
effects of the demographic disaster so
even though most people are old um they
will still have a powerful Nation
because of AI and
Robotics you know it's not just
technology that that drives a nation
there's something
called the moral and vitality of a
Nation the energy levels of a Nation you
know when your when in a nation all the
leaders are elderly people the moral
declines the energy of the nation
declines when you have youthful leaders
in a nation the moral goes
up and when the average age of the
population is very high let's say the
average age is 58 I assure you no M no
amount how of of Robotics no amount of
eii will change
that and Technology can only take you so
far unless unless you have technology
take over everything including decision
making so uh they will certainly
leverage technology they will put out
those robotic
soldiers robotic dog soldiers as well
with with machine guns on top they'll
have drones of all kinds they will have
ai in society Etc other nations will
also do the same thing eventually all
these wars will be automated
Wars um but I don't think it's is going
to offset the demographic disaster
because not everything is about war and
one doesn't want Wars I mean I don't
want a war with China I never want to
see another India China war and if our
leaders get things right then there
won't be a war then what happens let's
say everything goes well and there is no
war between China and the US China India
China whoever then what
happens then will you have robots and AI
replace humans you can't do that unless
you want to no longer exist exist so
nothing can replace your demographics
and that's the problem that China is
facing Abhijit
Cobra says what's the connection between
Hinduism and Indigenous American
religions of the Mayans azex Etc look
those religions in the Americas the
ancient Mayas Aztec tolc moch chimu
various cultures Etc these cultures were
polytheistic cultures but
it I'm not sure if there's a connection
between Hinduism and these cultures it's
possible that in the old days maybe
Indians traveled there we know that
Indians traveled to Australia across the
ocean significant distance away so it's
possible that the Indians could have
traveled to the Americans as well it is
possible we don't have evidence but it's
possible because the absence of evidence
is not evidence of absence so it's
possible but is there a connection
between Hinduism and these cultures look
many of these uh cultures are said to
have been rather blood thirsty Hinduism
is not a blood thirsty religion we don't
have human sacrifices we don't have
slavery we don't have all those things
these cultures apparently had that at
least it's what it's what the Europeans
claim the Spaniards claim that these
were barbaric brutal uh cultures that
had large scale human sacrifice and
there is some evidence of that they have
discovered the
tant in in Mexico the
hantle want to see
it well let's put it on why not because
why not what's the hant it's a skull
rack
hantle
so that's the hantle in
tlan Mexico and clearly this was part of
the
culture there and I I think we are all
pretty aware that no such thing could
ever exist in Hindu
so I'm not sure if there's a connection
between Hinduism and these cultures okay
in case there is well I I fail to see
how there
is okay let's take one more question
perhaps perhaps one more
question
uh what is it where are we what what
what feminism feminism J JP says
feminism is women aspiring to be like
men and wanting to have men's power
women hate the fact that they're born
female and they wish their men instead
of born being born a woman uh it's a
sentiment that's pretty common we all
know women girls Etc I think it's a
pretty common sentiment that girls women
Etc they they they say that they wish
they were born a man but look that's not
in our hands right the gender we are
born with it's it's it's not in our
hands you do the best with what you with
with what the gods gave you that's how
you do it and that's just what it is so
feminism look feminism started as the
movement for equal rights for women and
dignity and and
and that s of thing for women it was not
about women becoming men but but you're
right that later on it became a totally
different kind of movement it's no
longer now about being equal to men it's
about being Superior to men and it's
about oppressing men because allegedly
men oppressed women throughout history
you know we are one species we are two
sides of the same coin male or
female two
genders so yeah but you're right
feminism is very
problematic and and you know there are
very there are people who are
well-meaning people good people but they
go to
these go to these they do these courses
bachelor's degree master's degree
diploma whatever then they get
this ideology drilled into them and then
they they completely they transform they
become a totally different person and
they start being angry with men all men
are our enemies my father is my enemy my
brother is my enemy every man that was
ever born is an oppressor that's sort of
thing that is wrong it's about you know
this is the age-old tactic of dividing
society which is which is just a bad
thing so feminism started for a good
cause but then it's transformed to
something very different all right
okay I'm going to end this live stream
over here it's 2 hours and 15 minutes so
I think it's a good point to stop and I
will see you in the next live stream it
won't be next week because next week I
will be
traveling but I'm going to release some
other content on this channel next week
which will keep you uh which will
hopefully give you uh good value and the
live streams will continue in the week
after the next one all right so until
then take care and keep keep asking
questions and keep raising your
standards and I will see you reasonably
soon two weeks from now in the next live
stream until then take care thank you
bye